Murilo Lima

Goal: Software Engineer entry-level role.

Currently studying Full Stack Software Development at University College Dublin (UCD). Technologies: Phyton, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Github. (Open and willing to learn new technologies.) I am a Brazilian based in Dublin, Ireland. I have a Visa Stamp 1G and speak English and Portuguese. 12 years of experience in Digital Product Development for tech companies as PM / PO. Academic education in Business and Technology with a Master's degree in Software Engineering. Certified Scrum Master CSM (Scrum Alliance) and Team Kanban Practitioner - TKP (Kanban University).

E-mail: muriloserafimlima@gmail.com

Phone: +353 083 206 9718

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omurilolima/

Github: https://github.com/omurilolima

Work experience

Senior Product Owner, 01/2021 to 09/2022

C6 Bank - São Paulo, SP - Brazil

C6 Bank is one of the fastest-growing digital banks worldwide with over 20 million customers in Brazil. Coordinate end-to-end delivery of product roadmap of 5 squads (Engineering, Design, Product, and Business) for financial products like checking account, credit cards, loyalty programs, insurance, and loans.

- Writing Agile-based stories that conform to best practices including acceptance criteria, positive and negative paths, etc;
- Mobile first products for Android and iOS.

Main accomplishment:

- Developed C6 Yellow from scratch in 2021. C6 Yellow is a product focused on the young (under 18) and has a dedicated app.
- Acquired 50k in the first guarter post-launch.
- 35k MAU was measured by the total users who did at least one transaction within the month.
- Activation rate of 75%, measured by new users who requested account opening, completed the product onboarding and performed the first transaction.
- Led lean product development process in a multidisciplinary team composed of 32 members (Product Marketing Manager, Software Engineers, QAs, Business Analysts, Designer, and UX Researcher).

Product Manager, 08/2019 to 01/2021

Acqio - Recife, PE - Brazil

- Acgio is a fintech startup focused on B2B payment options for SMEs.
- Ran a data democratisation initiative to provide information to the non-technical internal user and facilitate the follow-up of the metrics aligned with company Objectives and Key results.
- Led the automation process of anticipation credit products. Optimised 40% of lead time.
 Increased EUR 10 million in revenue.
- Implemented go-to-market strategy of a B2B SaaS Subscription engine that allowed it to offer products based on a monthly recurrency business model. Acquired +10.000 new customers with more than EUR 1 million TPV. Acquired EUR 100K in Monthly Recurring Revenue (MRR).
- Managing product lifecycle, from ideation to post-launch.
- Integrating usability studies, metrics, and market/customer research into product requirements.
- Implemented strategic and operational KPIs aligned with the corporate strategy.

Project Manager, 07/2017 to 08/2019

Joy Street - Recife, PE - Brazil

Joy Street is a B2B Edtech focused on developing gamified online education platforms.

- Increased monthly active users from 0 to 50k, as measured by users who completed at least 1 lesson.
- Improved processes of planning and implementation of new positions using agile strategies and practices. This effort contributed to increasing the throughput by 11x and decreasing Lead Time considerably.
- A scaled team from 12 to 24 members in the first 6 months to carry through a dual-track development.
- Managed clients such as Fiat Chrysler Automobiles (FCA), Unilever, CESAR, Porto Digital, SEBRAE, SENAI, Rede Globo, Saraiva, and Natura.
- Planned, validated, and implemented scope, technical specifications, schedule, cost, quality, risks, resources, and acquisitions with internal and external partners.
- Mobile first products for Android and iOS.

Product Manager, Founder, 02/2012 to 07/2017

Geek Cafe - Remote

- From 0 to 300.000+ monthly active users.
- Acquiring a customer base with global product companies like Petrobrás, Heineken, Coca-Cola, Samsung, Ford, Hyundai, Disney, Marvel, Warner, Netflix, etc.
- Managed product lifecycle, from ideation to post-launch.

Project Manager, 11/2009 to 07/2016

SOFTEX - Recife, PE - Brazil

- Implemented the maturity models CMMI, MPS.Br, and MPT.Br (Improvement of the Brazilian Software Testing Process) and market planning in 40 startups.
- Enhanced Monthly Recurring Revenue (MRR) among the companies we worked for by 10% higher than the average among the 200 startups participating in the annual survey of ICT Companies embarked in the Digital Port of Recife for 3 consecutive years.
- Planned and led simultaneous small and medium-sized projects with continuous improvement management processes, innovation, and high-quality software development within 90+ startups (B2B, B2C) in 6 years.

Languages

- Portuguese Native proficiency
- English Full professional proficiency

Education

- Full-Stack Software Development professional diploma at University College Dublin (UCD) & Code Institute - 2022 (Ongoing)
- MSc Computer Software Engineering at CESAR School, 2019 to 2022.
- MSc Computer Science at Universidade Federal de Pernambuco (UFPE), 2014 to 2016.
 - 100% of credits completed. Stopped due to health issues that I no longer have today.
- MBA Digital Marketing at Estácio de Sá University, 2011 to 2012.
- BA Business and Computer Systems Analysis at Maurício de Nassau University, 2006 to 2009.

Licenses & certifications

- Product Management, Produtos Incríveis, 2020.
- Team Kanban Practitioner, Kanban University, 2019.
- Certified Scrum Product Owner, Scrum Institute, 2019.
- PMP® Certification Training Course, 2018
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM), Agile Development, Scrum Alliance, 2017.